{
    "id": "Covid-19_18",
    "claim": "Queretaro health sector members denied the application of the Blue Code scheme to care for patients who are more likely to survive COVID-19. “In disaster medicine it is to define which people have the most chance of having a quality life in the absence of resources. Suppose there are no fans in a hospital; in the face of this degree, in which capacities are exceeded, survival is analyzed to care for those who may have the highest quality of life,” explained Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM). Until the end of this edition, information from the state administration showed that on January 12, hospitalization in the entity had reached 59. 3 per cent. The government also warned that because of the trend in active cases, “we are very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time this week.”. The term ‘blue code', Carlos Casillas reiterated, has been used more in war medicine or disasters of great magnitude. “We haven't come to that yet and I still don't know if it's being done in Queretaro. At least there is no formal indication,” said the CRUM coordinator. ‘HOSPITALS ARE CONTAINING STRATEGIES' Dr. Hugo Daniel Cerrillo, director of Hospital General Queretaro, ruled that this scheme should be applied or implemented in the hospitals of the entity. “It has not been established or considered. All hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient's severity; we work through an international triage to optimize resources and care times. The attention has never been denied, it has been dilated, but every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation,” explained the doctor, who said that before thinking of a ‘war scenario', more beds and spaces would be enabled. ‘THE CAMES ARE OCCUPED IN THE STATE' The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández commented that hospitals in Queretaro are being filled. According to the system of the Severe Acute Respiratory Infection Network (IRAG) and until January 12, the Ismael Vázquez Ortiz center, of the ISSSTE; the Regional General Hospital 2 in El Marques, of the IMSS; and the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Río, of the IMSS, are the places that reported 100 percent occupancy of beds in general hospitalization. “The truth is that they are practically full. Many patients leave, but no income level. As you graduate 10 people, 20 or 25 arrive; the replacement rate is brutal, which does not lower the level,” he shared. On the ‘blue code', the doctor clarified that it is a war triage and that there was a distortion on the issue in Mexico City, but denied that it was applied in hospitals. FALTY OF PERSONALIn the worst scenario some nosocomios may adopt the ‘blue code' as they no longer have room for manoeuvre, said Dr. Luis Vázquez, who works in a Queretano hospital, but before arriving at the choice of who lives or dies, the lack of human resources may arise first, he said, since, he said, the medical staff is exhausted. “The issue, if it goes on like this, could lead us not to reach the medical staff, rather than to have to choose who lives or not, would go through the issue of who cares for the sick,” he said. When has the ‘Blue CODE' been used?In 1962, Seattle had to decide who was a candidate for the first hemodialysis treatments. In a Life magazine news story titled, “They decide who lives and who dies,” the story of one of the patients who was able to survive through treatment.. and the decision of the seven-citizens committee that decided who lived and who was not a candidate for treatment was told. On March 6, 2020, the Italian Society of Anesthesia, Analgesia, Resuscitation and Intensive Care (SIAARTI) developed a guide of ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments, taking into account the exceptional conditions of imbalance between needs (the number of infected and their requirements) and available resources (the number of ICU beds and artificial respirators). The use of triage (classification) resulted in a structured system that placed patients according to the degree of urgency they present, prioritized their assistance, ensuring that those assessed as most urgent were those treated as a priority. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "amqueretaro.com",
    "date": "14/01/2021",
    "veracity": 1,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "Queretaro health sector members denied the ‘blue code' of the Blue the medical staff care the ‘blue code' patients who are more likely to survive some nosocomios .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that Queretaro health sector members denied the 'blue code' of the Blue?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are the blue code patients who are more likely to survive some nosocomios?",
                    "score": 0.6425,
                    "answers": "blue code|nmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the mortality rate of the Blue code patients?",
                    "score": 0.5676,
                    "answers": "more likely to survive some nosocomios|acomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the blue code of the Blue Code patients?",
                    "score": 0.552,
                    "answers": "Queretaro health sector members|nsubj\tto survive some nosocomios|xcomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "some nosocomios people have the most the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) a quality life in the absence of resources.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that some nosocomios people have the most a quality life in the absence of resources?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many nosocomios people have the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM)?",
                    "score": 0.7149,
                    "answers": "some nosocomios people|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does CRUM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.6304,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that some nosocomios people have the most the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) a quality life in the absence of resources|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tsome|det\tthat some nosocomios people have the most the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) a quality life in the absence of resources|ccomp\tthe|det\tthe|det\tMedical|compound\tEmergency|compound\tRegulatory|compound\tthe Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) a quality life in the absence of resources|dobj\t(|punct\tCRUM|appos\t)|punct\ta|det\tquality|compound\ta quality life in the absence of resources|appos\tthe|det\tresources|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the acronym CRUM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.6294,
                    "answers": "nosocomios|compound\tthe most|dobj\tin the absence of resources|prep\tthe absence of resources|pobj\tof resources|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Suppose there are no fans in a hospital; The issue degree, in which Dr. Luis Vázquez, who works in a Queretano hospital exceeded, survival is analyzed to care for those The issue the highest quality of life,” explained Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) hospitals in Queretaro Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) the IMSS the medical staff .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that Suppose there are no fans in a hospital?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many fans does Dr. Luis Vázquez work in a Queretano hospital?",
                    "score": 0.7306,
                    "answers": "in which Dr. Luis Vázquez , who works in a Queretano hospital exceeded|relcl\tin Queretaro|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many fans are in a hospital in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6752,
                    "answers": "Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) hospitals in Queretaro|nsubj\tthe Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) hospitals in Queretaro|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. Luis Vázquez do to care for the issue the highest quality of life?",
                    "score": 0.6488,
                    "answers": "The issue degree , in which Dr. Luis Vázquez , who works in a Queretano hospital exceeded , survival to care for those The issue the highest quality of life|nsubjpass\tThe issue degree , in which Dr. Luis Vázquez , who works in a Queretano hospital exceeded , survival to care for those The issue the highest quality of life is analyzed|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was Dr. Luis Vázquez's death rate?",
                    "score": 0.6159,
                    "answers": "survival|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Where is Dr. Luis Vázquez working?",
                    "score": 0.563,
                    "answers": "a Queretano hospital|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "the medical staff of this edition, information from the state administration showed that on January 12, hospitalization in Queretaro had reached 59.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the number of hospitalizations in Queretaro on January 12?",
                    "answer": "59"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the hospitalization rate in Queretaro on January 12?",
                    "score": 0.6524,
                    "answers": "that on January 12 , hospitalization in Queretaro had reached 59|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "3 per cent.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported that 3 per cent of the population had a 3% unemployment rate on 14/01/2021?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the percentage of fraud on amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.7072,
                    "answers": "that 3 per cent|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5559,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that 3 per cent|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\t3|nummod\tper|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The government also warned that because of the trend in active cases, The attention very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time The attention .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 14/01/2021 that The government warned that because of the trend in active cases, The attention very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the most recent trend of illegal immigration?",
                    "score": 0.6188,
                    "answers": "The attention very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the current rate of illegal immigration at the southern border?",
                    "score": 0.5244,
                    "answers": "very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many active cases were there in 2015?",
                    "score": 0.4956,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that The government also warned that because of the trend in active cases , The attention very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time The attention|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the trend of active cases?",
                    "score": 0.4904,
                    "answers": "the trend in active cases , The attention very likely to break the 60 percent border for the first time|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between active cases and the 60 percent border?",
                    "score": 0.4017,
                    "answers": "the 60 percent border|dobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The term ‘blue code', Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) reiterated, has been used more in war medicine or disasters of the IMSS magnitude.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Casillas?",
                    "answer": "state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the blue code being used in war medicine or disasters of IMSS magnitude?",
                    "score": 0.6862,
                    "answers": "that|mark\tThe|det\t'|punct\t,|punct\t,|punct\t(|punct\t)|punct\t,|punct\tmore|advmod\tor|cc"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does the acronym CRUM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.6512,
                    "answers": "state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|appos\tof the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|prep\tthe Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the blue code and the IMSS magnitude?",
                    "score": 0.627,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that The term ‘ blue code ' , Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) reiterated , has been used more in war medicine or disasters of the IMSS magnitude|ROOT\tthe|det\thas|aux\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Casillas?",
                    "score": 0.6212,
                    "answers": "Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What doesCRUM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.621,
                    "answers": "Regulatory|compound"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“We haven't come to that yet and Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) still don't know if it's being done in Queretaro .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Casillas?",
                    "answer": "state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long has it been since Carlos Casillas has been in charge of the CRUM?",
                    "score": 0.5439,
                    "answers": "still|advmod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Casillas?",
                    "score": 0.5304,
                    "answers": "Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between Carlos Casillas and the state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM)?",
                    "score": 0.513,
                    "answers": "on 14/01/2021|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the construction of the Queretaro Medical Emergency Regulatory Center?",
                    "score": 0.5,
                    "answers": "that “ We have n't come to that yet and Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM ) still do n't know if it 's being done in Queretaro|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the hospital in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.4931,
                    "answers": "if it 's being done in Queretaro|ccomp\tin Queretaro|prep"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "At least there is no formal indication,” said Carlos Casillas, state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who is Carlos Casillas?",
                    "answer": "state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the relationship between the state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center (CRUM) and Carlos Casillas?",
                    "score": 0.5672,
                    "answers": "formal|amod"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the definition of a medical emergency?",
                    "score": 0.5235,
                    "answers": "Medical Emergency|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does CRUM stand for?",
                    "score": 0.5161,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that At least there is no formal indication , ” said Carlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|ROOT\tCarlos Casillas , state coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|nsubj\tstate|compound\tstate coordinator of the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|appos\tof the Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|prep\tMedical|compound\tRegulatory|compound\tthe Medical Emergency Regulatory Center ( CRUM )|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.4075,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "‘HOSPITALS ARE CONTAINING The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández Dr. hospitals in Queretaro Cerrillo, director of Hospital General Queretaro, ruled the ‘blue code' this the ‘blue code' should be applied or implemented in the hospitals of Queretaro .",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that 'HOSPITALSARE CONTAINING The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández Dr. hospitals in Queretaro Cerrillo, director of Hospital General Queretaro, ruled the 'blue code'?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What was Miguel Hernández Dr. Hospital in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6577,
                    "answers": "The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández Dr. hospitals in Queretaro|dobj\tMiguel|compound\tHospital|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Cerrillo rule about the blue code?",
                    "score": 0.6552,
                    "answers": "Cerrillo , director of Hospital General Queretaro , ruled the ‘ blue code ' this the ‘ blue code ' should be applied or implemented in the hospitals of Queretaro|ROOT"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What did Dr. Miguel Hernández say about the Blue Code?",
                    "score": 0.6444,
                    "answers": "Dr. hospitals in Queretaro|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the blue code for hospitals in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6279,
                    "answers": "implemented in the hospitals of Queretaro|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Hernández Dr. hospitals in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6139,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that ‘ HOSPITALS ARE CONTAINING The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández Dr. hospitals in Queretaro|ROOT"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "All hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient's severity; we work through an international triage to optimize resources and care times.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that All hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient's severity?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient's severity?",
                    "score": 0.8397,
                    "answers": "the patient 's severity|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5706,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that All hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient 's severity|ccomp\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tAll|det\tAll hospitals|nsubj\tto|aux\tcare|dobj\tthe|det\tthe patient 's|poss\t's|case\t;|punct\twe|nsubj\tamqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that All hospitals have strategies to optimize care according to the patient 's severity ; we work through an international triage to optimize resources and care times|ROOT\tthrough an international triage|prep\tan|det\tinternational|amod\tan international triage|pobj\tto|aux\tresources and care times|dobj\tand|cc\tcare|compound\tcare times|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The attention has never been denied, it has been dilated, but every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation,” explained the doctor, who said that before thinking of a ‘war scenario', more beds and spaces would be enabled.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that Every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many beds and spaces would be added during the war scenario?",
                    "score": 0.5763,
                    "answers": "who said that before thinking of a ‘ war scenario ' , more beds and spaces would be enabled|relcl\tthat before thinking of a ‘ war scenario ' , more beds and spaces would be enabled|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the difference between a doctor's attention and a patient's attention?",
                    "score": 0.5589,
                    "answers": "that The attention has never been denied , it has been dilated , but every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.4155,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that The attention has never been denied , it has been dilated , but every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation|ccomp\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tThe|det\tThe attention|nsubjpass\thas|aux\tnever|neg\tbeen|auxpass\t,|punct\tit|nsubjpass\thas|aux\tbeen|auxpass\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tevery|det\tevery patient|nsubj\tevery patient deserves a time of care and evaluation|conj\ta|det\ta time of care and evaluation|dobj\tof care and evaluation|prep\tcare and evaluation|pobj\tand|cc\tevaluation|conj\t,|punct\t”|punct\tamqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that The attention has never been denied , it has been dilated , but every patient deserves a time of care and evaluation , ” explained the doctor , who said that before thinking of a ‘ war scenario ' , more beds and spaces would be enabled|ROOT\tthe|det\t,|punct\twho|nsubj\tthat|mark\tbefore thinking of a ‘ war scenario|prep\tthinking of a ‘ war scenario|pcomp\tof a ‘ war scenario|prep\ta|det\t‘|punct\twar|compound\ta ‘ war scenario|pobj\t'|punct\t,|punct\tmore|amod\tmore beds and spaces|nsubjpass\tand|cc\twould|aux\tbe|auxpass"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "‘THE CAMES ARE OCCUPED IN THE STATE' The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández commented that hospitals in Queretaro are being filled.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who commented that hospitals in Queretaro are being filled?",
                    "answer": "Miguel Hernández"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many hospitals are closed in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6935,
                    "answers": "on 14/01/2021|prep\thospitals in Queretaro|nsubjpass\tin Queretaro|prep\tthat hospitals in Queretaro are being filled|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many vacant hospitals are in Queretaro according to Miguel Hernández?",
                    "score": 0.6572,
                    "answers": "IN THE STATE|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the number of vacant hospitals in Queretaro?",
                    "score": 0.6208,
                    "answers": "are|aux\tbeing|auxpass"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who is Miguel Hernández?",
                    "score": 0.5768,
                    "answers": "The Queretano epidemiologist Miguel Hernández|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.4924,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "According to the system of the Severe Acute Respiratory Infection Network (IRAG) and until January 12, the Ismael Vázquez Ortiz center, of the ISSSTE; the Regional General Hospital 2 in El Marques, of the IMSS; and the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Río, of the IMSS, are the places that reported 100 percent occupancy of beds in general hospitalization.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What percentage of beds did the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Ro have?",
                    "answer": "100 percent"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the number of beds in general hospital in San Jual del Rio?",
                    "score": 0.6612,
                    "answers": "the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Río , of the IMSS ,|conj\tof Zone 3|prep\t3|nummod\tin San Jual del Río|prep\tSan|compound\tJual|compound\tdel|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many beds were in the Ismael Vázquez Ortiz Ortiz center until January 12?",
                    "score": 0.6516,
                    "answers": "until January 12|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the hospitals in El Marques?",
                    "score": 0.6148,
                    "answers": "to the system of the Severe Acute Respiratory Infection Network ( IRAG )|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the system of the Severe Acute Respiratory Infection Network (IRAG)?",
                    "score": 0.608,
                    "answers": "the system of the Severe Acute Respiratory Infection Network ( IRAG )|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the hospital in El Marques?",
                    "score": 0.5916,
                    "answers": "the Ismael Vázquez Ortiz center , of the ISSSTE ; the Regional General Hospital 2 in El Marques , of the IMSS ; and the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Río , of the IMSS ,|nsubj\tthe Regional General Hospital 2 in El Marques , of the IMSS ; and the General Hospital of Zone 3 in San Jual del Río , of the IMSS ,|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“The truth is that they are practically full.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that “The truth is that they are practically full”?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the truth of amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5698,
                    "answers": "The truth|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5528,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that “ The truth is that they are practically full|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tThe|det\tthat “ The truth is that they are practically full|ccomp\tthat|mark\tthey|nsubj\tthat they are practically full|ccomp\tpractically|advmod\tpractically full|acomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Many patients leave, but no income level.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What website reported on 14/01/2021 that many patients leave, but no income level?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many patients leave the country each year?",
                    "score": 0.863,
                    "answers": "Many patients|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the income level of patients who leave the country?",
                    "score": 0.8597,
                    "answers": "that Many patients leave , but no income level|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What income level does amqueretaro.com cover?",
                    "score": 0.849,
                    "answers": "income|compound\tno income level|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5927,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that Many patients leave , but no income level|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tMany|amod\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tno|det"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "As you graduate 10 people, 20 or 25 arrive; the replacement rate is brutal, which does not lower the level,” he shared.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that as you graduate 10 people, 20 or 25 arrive; the replacement rate is brutal?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What is the replacement rate for people who graduate from college?",
                    "score": 0.6841,
                    "answers": "on 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tAs|mark\tyou|nsubj\tAs you graduate|advcl\t10 people , 20 or 25|nsubj\t,|punct\t20 or 25|appos\tor|cc\t;|punct\tthe|det\tthe replacement rate|nsubj\t,|punct\twhich|nsubj\tdoes|aux\tnot|neg\tthe|det\tthe level|dobj\t,|punct\t”|punct\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "On the ‘blue code', the doctor clarified that it is a war triage and that there was a distortion on the issue in Mexico City, but denied that it was applied in hospitals.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that On the blue code, the doctor clarified that it is a war triage and that there was a distortion on the issue in Mexico City?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the doctor say about the \"blue code\"?",
                    "score": 0.5622,
                    "answers": "on 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tthe|det\t‘|punct\t'|punct\t,|punct\tthe|det\tthe doctor|nsubj\tthat|mark\tit|nsubj\tthat it is a war triage and that there was a distortion on the issue in Mexico City|advcl\twar|compound\ta war triage|attr\tand|cc\tthat|mark\tthere|expl\tthat there was a distortion on the issue in Mexico City|conj\ta distortion on the issue in Mexico City|attr\tthe|det\tin Mexico City|prep\t,|punct\tbut|cc\tdenied that it was applied in hospitals|conj\tthat|mark\tit|nsubjpass\twas|auxpass\tthat it was applied in hospitals|ccomp\tin hospitals|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the blue code in hospitals?",
                    "score": 0.5269,
                    "answers": "hospitals|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "FALTY OF PERSONALIn the worst scenario some nosocomios may adopt the ‘blue code' as they no longer have room for manoeuvre, said Dr. Luis Vázquez, who works in a Queretano hospital, but before arriving at the choice of who lives or dies, the lack of human resources may arise first, he said, since, he said, the medical staff is exhausted.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What was the worst scenario some nosocomios may adopt the 'blue code'?",
                    "answer": "FALTY OF PERSONALIn"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What hospital does Dr. Luis Vázquez work for?",
                    "score": 0.7005,
                    "answers": "a Queretano hospital|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is Dr. Luis Vázquez's role in the Queretano hospital?",
                    "score": 0.5603,
                    "answers": "in a Queretano hospital|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the blue code?",
                    "score": 0.5119,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that FALTY OF PERSONALIn the worst scenario some nosocomios may adopt the ‘ blue code ' as they no longer have room for manoeuvre|ccomp\tsome nosocomios may adopt the ‘ blue code ' as they no longer have room for manoeuvre|ccomp\tblue|amod\tthe ‘ blue code '|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the lack of human resources for doctors and medical staff?",
                    "score": 0.488,
                    "answers": "the lack of human resources|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "“The issue, if it goes on like this, could lead us not to reach the medical staff, rather than to have to choose who lives or not, would go through the issue of who cares for the sick,” he said.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that \"The issue, if it goes on like this, could lead us not to reach the medical staff?\"",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How many people care for the sick per year?",
                    "score": 0.5841,
                    "answers": "would go through the issue of who cares for the sick|dep\tthrough the issue of who cares for the sick|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the medical staff that care for the sick?",
                    "score": 0.5802,
                    "answers": "to have to choose who lives or not|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many medical staff are there in the United States?",
                    "score": 0.5659,
                    "answers": "The issue , if it goes on like this , could lead us not to reach the medical staff , rather than to have to choose who lives or not , would go through the issue of who cares for the sick|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.4261,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that “ The issue , if it goes on like this , could lead us not to reach the medical staff , rather than to have to choose who lives or not , would go through the issue of who cares for the sick , ” he said|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\t“|punct\tThe|det\tThe issue|nsubj\t,|punct\tif|mark\tit|nsubj\tif it goes on like this|advcl\ton|prt\tlike this|prep\tthis|pobj\t,|punct\tcould|aux\tus|dobj\tnot|neg\tto|aux\tthe|det\tmedical|amod\tthe medical staff|dobj\t,|punct\trather|advmod\trather than|cc\tto|aux\tto|aux\tto choose who lives or not|xcomp\twho|nsubj\twho lives or not|ccomp\tor|cc\tnot|conj\t,|punct\twould|aux\tthe|det\tthe issue of who cares for the sick|pobj\twho|nsubj\tfor the sick|prep\tthe|det\t,|punct\t”|punct\the|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "When has the ‘Blue CODE' been used?In 1962, Seattle had to decide who was a candidate for the first hemodialysis treatments.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported on 14/01/2021 that When has the 'Blue CODE' been used?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did Seattle do to decide who was a candidate for the first hemodialysis treatment?",
                    "score": 0.854,
                    "answers": "to decide who was a candidate for the first hemodialysis treatments|xcomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is hemodialysis?",
                    "score": 0.7997,
                    "answers": "hemodialysis|compound"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the Blue Code?",
                    "score": 0.73,
                    "answers": "the|det\tBlue|amod\ta|det\tthe|det"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is amqueretaro.com?",
                    "score": 0.5892,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that When has the ‘ Blue CODE ' been used?In 1962|ROOT\ton 14/01/2021|prep\tthat|mark\tWhen|advmod\thas|aux\t‘|punct\t'|punct\tbeen|auxpass\t,|punct\tto|aux\twho|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "In a Life magazine news story titled, “They decide who lives and who dies,” the story of one of the patients who was able to survive through treatment.. and the decision of the seven-citizens committee that decided who lived and who was not a candidate for treatment was told.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "In what magazine was the story titled \"They decide who lives and who dies\"?",
                    "answer": "Life magazine"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Did the seven-citizens committee decide who lived and who was not a candidate for treatment?",
                    "score": 0.6394,
                    "answers": "of the seven - citizens committee that decided who lived and who was not a candidate for treatment|prep\tnot|neg"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many patients were able to survive through treatment?",
                    "score": 0.5696,
                    "answers": "the story of one of the patients who was able to survive through treatment .. and|nsubjpass\tto survive through treatment|xcomp\ttreatment|pobj\ttreatment|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "Who decides who lives and who dies?",
                    "score": 0.5397,
                    "answers": "titled , “ They decide who lives and who dies|acl\t“ They decide who lives and who dies|ccomp\twho lives and who dies|ccomp"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "On March 6, 2020, the Italian Society of Anesthesia, Analgesia, Resuscitation and Intensive Care (SIAARTI) developed a guide of ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments, taking into account the exceptional conditions of imbalance between needs (the number of infected and their requirements) and available resources (the number of ICU beds and artificial respirators).",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What factors were taken into account in the ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments?",
                    "answer": "imbalance between needs (the number of infected and their requirements) and available resources"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What ethical recommendations were made by the Italian Society of Anesthesia, Analgesia, Resuscitation and Intensive Care?",
                    "score": 0.8397,
                    "answers": "of ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatment?",
                    "score": 0.6543,
                    "answers": "Analgesia , Resuscitation and Intensive Care|conj\ta guide of ethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments|dobj\tethical|amod\tethical recommendations for admission to and suspension of intensive treatments|pobj\tfor admission to and suspension of intensive treatments|prep\tadmission to and suspension of intensive treatments|pobj\tsuspension of intensive treatments|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the number of ICU beds and artificial respirators?",
                    "score": 0.6371,
                    "answers": "available resources ( the number of ICU beds and artificial respirators|conj\tthe number of ICU beds and artificial respirators|appos"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What does SIAARTI stand for?",
                    "score": 0.6067,
                    "answers": "Anesthesia , Analgesia , Resuscitation and Intensive Care|pobj\tResuscitation and Intensive Care|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the conditions of imbalance between needs and available resources?",
                    "score": 0.5551,
                    "answers": "exceptional|amod"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "The use of triage (classification) resulted in a structured system that placed patients according to the degree of urgency they present, prioritized their assistance, ensuring that those assessed as most urgent were those treated as a priority.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "Who reported that triage resulted in a structured system that placed patients according to the degree of urgency they present?",
                    "answer": "amqueretaro.com"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the use of triage (classification) help patients?",
                    "score": 0.8357,
                    "answers": "patients|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What were the patients assessed as most urgent?",
                    "score": 0.7424,
                    "answers": "those assessed as most urgent|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What was the purpose of triage classification?",
                    "score": 0.7035,
                    "answers": "in a structured system that placed patients according to the degree of urgency they present , prioritized their assistance , ensuring that those assessed as most urgent were those treated as a priority|prep"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the purpose of triage?",
                    "score": 0.6783,
                    "answers": "amqueretaro.com reported on 14/01/2021 that The use of triage ( classification ) resulted in a structured system that placed patients according to the degree of urgency they present , prioritized their assistance , ensuring that those assessed as most urgent were those treated as a priority|ROOT\tof triage ( classification )|prep\ttriage ( classification )|pobj\tstructured|amod\taccording to the degree of urgency they present|prep\tprioritized their assistance ,|dep"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}